You really don't want to get a Ph.D.?
Absolutely not.
Then why don't you just join us at Flight Control?
This year, I want to organize
the promising newcomers
and form a
Muxing Team.
It's entirely based on young people's concepts.
The tasks
will be more flexible
and freer.
Don't you have internship experience?
Why don't you think about it?
Mr. Qin, please don't try to persuade me.
I don't want to go anywhere.
I don't want to persuade you.
I won't lead a horse to water and make it drink.
I wouldn't do such a thing.
Wouldn't that make me just like your mother?
Actually, you should be able to understand
your mother's good intentions.
At her age,
a son means everything
to a mother.
Every grade you've gotten since you were a child,
you can see how much weight it holds
in her heart, right?
Of course, you are a child
who hates being controlled.
You're born rebellious.
The more you arrange for me,
the less I want it.
Right?
But,
the current situation between you two,
living under the same roof every day,
won't it just intensify the conflict?
How about this?
Flight Control recently allocated a dorm building,
a bachelor dorm.
They are all brand new,
fully furnished.
I can arrange for you
to go there and hide for a while.
What do you say?
Of course, our side
is strictly managed.
It's a closed management system,
you can't just come and go as you please.
I don't know if you can stand it.
Think about it.
If you come,
I'll go talk to your mom.
I've also communicated with Mr. Qiao.
He will talk to your mother too.
Mr. Qin,
thank you for the invitation,
but I really have no such plans right now.
You have your plans,
and I have my own rules.
I like your personality.
Weiwei,
why did you just get back?
How was the Flight Control interview?
Come, do me a favor.
Press this here.
Don't move.
Seeing you so listless,
did you fail?
That's fine.
If this path doesn't work out,
let's not force it.
Doesn't your major have many career paths?
Hurry up and find a company to work for.
Didn't many companies give you those,
what do you call them,
offer letters?
Pick one carefully.
I plan
to try the Space City Archives.
With your major,
what can you do at the archives?
Probably an archives administrator.
Let me tell you,
your father is a cautionary tale for you,
a negative example.
Back in the day, at least
I was a communications equipment technician.
I was spoiled for choice and got confused.
Out of so many companies,
I just had to pick a pager company.
My youth and the first half of my life
were all wasted there.
Did someone cast a spell on you?
You insist on being an administrator at Space City.
No way.
I'm going anyway.
Even if it's just an administrator,
it's an administrator at Space City.
What do you know?
This is called finding a new path.
I rejected all those job offers.
Enough, stay out of this.
I can decide for myself.
You...
Stop right there!
You rejected them all?
So many people fight tooth and nail
just to get in but can't,
and you rejected them?
On what grounds did you reject them?
Do you have the final say or do I?
Go find a company and work properly.
I won't listen to you.
If you don't let me go, my mom will.
Your son is going to work in aerospace!
I am your father!
I...
What's going on? Is everything okay?
It's nothing.
Fine, let's eat.
Let's eat first. We'll talk after dinner.
Weiwei.
You truly live up to taking your mother's surname.
Every move you make is just like her.
Back then, when your mom wanted to do logistics in aerospace,
your grandma was strongly against it.
She said,
'Our daughter is a proper
college student majoring in statistics,
what is she going to do at Space City?
What can she achieve by doing logistics?'
I remember because of this,
your mom and your grandma argued
so fiercely.
To be honest, if I wasn't in the middle
mediating between them,
I'm telling you, they would have fought.
I was just a geography teacher,
if my daughter could work in aerospace,
what else was there to say?
Go for it.
At the time, I just felt that
they always worked overtime there,
and I was worried
it would exhaust my daughter.
Ultimately,
children grow up.
The path they take is the one they choose.
The life they live
is the life they choose.
As fathers and mothers,
no matter how much you love your kids,
you can't live
their whole lives for them.
Right?
What should a father do?
A father must be able to shoulder responsibilities.
You... tell your dad...
Ever since he came to our Wu family,
your mom has been so busy working in aerospace.
He manages everything inside and outside the house,
taking care of you
and raising you with all his might,
bringing you up to this age.
Is it easy for him?
He also takes care of us old folks.
It's so hard for him.
Whether we work in the archives
or flight control,
as long as it's in aerospace, it's fine.
Just go report to the archives properly.
Weiwei.
Mom.
How did you get so dirty?
Sit down.
Let mom wipe it for you.
Are you a little dirty cat?
Look at your helmet.
Let's wipe it.
Mom.
I miss you.
Weiwei,
did something happen?
Tell mom.
Nothing much.
It's just that I encountered many things
and always get rejected.
I don't know
if there's any point in holding on.
How could there be no point?
Holding on is the point.
Weiwei,
others may reject you,
but what about yourself?
Don't be afraid.
No matter what others say,
Mom will always believe in you.
It's clean now.
Mom,
let's go home.
Shall we go eat?
Mom will make you sweet and sour ribs.
Okay.
Today at 19:41,
the Zhengtu-7 Yao-2 carrier rocket,
carrying the Longzhou-1 cargo spacecraft,
was ignited and launched at the Wenchang Space Launch Site in China.
About 596 seconds later,
the spacecraft successfully separated from the rocket
and entered the designated orbit.
The launch was a complete success.
Next,
let's invite Chief Designer Chu Jiajia
to give a brief introduction.
Next,
Longzhou-1 will pass through the 400-meter
and 120-meter parking points,
and finally complete
the rendezvous and docking with Longgong-2.
Xiaoqi.
Come, get up.
Be good.
Son,
let dad tell you some news.
You must not sell me out.
Mr. Qin from the other day
has already promised your mom
to help you find a reliable mentor.
Ying Ziqi.
Yesterday, your mom
put away your IDs.
Tell me,
if you lack these,
how can you go out
and get a job?
So for now,
just eat and drink as usual.
Let's just wait and see.
What are you doing?
No, be gentle.
If your mom hears us,
we're both dead.
What are you going to do?
Let's talk this out.
Where are you going?
Xiaoqi.
You're slipping away, aren't you?
Don't be so disloyal.
Aren't you selling me out?
Think about it.
I've lived with your mom for over 20 years.
If I fall out with her
over your little issue,
is it worth it?
Besides, your mom treats you like this
for a reason.
You should understand her.
Dad,
I've thought about it for a long time.
I haven't figured out what I really want.
Don't get worked up.
Keep your voice down.
But I know exactly what I don't want.
I don't want this kind of life.
I don't want this kind of family.
And I definitely don't want
a mom like this.
Ziqi.
What are you doing?
If your mom hears this,
she'll be so sad.
What are you doing?
Are you really leaving?
You're too disloyal.
Hello, Mr. Qin.
I'm Ying Ziqi.
You mentioned before,
is the quota for flight control still open?
It is.
We've been waiting for you.
Thank you, Mr. Qin.
Hello.
Go forward, it's here.
Hello, sir.
Are you new?
If you need to look up materials, go over there,
and swipe your badge yourself.
No, sir.
I'm here for the archives.
I'm here to report for duty.
Archivist?
Are you Wu Wei?
Navigation, Guidance and Control.
Why didn't you interview at the Flight Control Center?
I...
I was originally going to Flight Control.
But I got rejected.
I heard from Mr. Qin Bojun
that the archives are hiring.
So I wanted to give it a try.
It's a way to fulfill my space dream.
I've wanted to be an astronaut since I was a kid.
But because my eyesight is poor,
I was rejected for that too.
But I've figured it out.
I just need to adapt.
As long as I can work in the space industry,
I'll take any position.
OK.
You are still a kid with a dream.
Not bad.
I like it.
If not an astronaut, then flight control.
If not flight control, then the archives.
What do you take my archives for?
A stepping stone or an asylum?
No, no, sir.
Sir.
I...
I didn't take the archives as a stepping stone,
nor an asylum.
I don't think an archivist
is a bad job.
Rest assured, since I'm here,
I will work hard.
All right, fine.
You can go.
Please, sir.
Give me one more chance.
Didn't I give you a chance?
You did?
This is...
I'm assigning you a vehicle.
Let me tell you,
it's for official use only.
I get a vehicle?
Of course.
This is our archives'
ancestral BMW.
What are you looking at?
I saw one over there.
I was thinking,
the treasure of our archives
should at least be a rocket model.
So...
See the pen?
Do you know what kind of pen it is?
A fountain pen.
Very smart.
Isn't that obvious?
Yes.
Do you know why I put it there?
Because it's very memorable.
Do you know who gave it to me?
I don't know.
Let me tell you,
you are not qualified to know yet.
Go, report to your dorm.
Off you go.
I'll come to work tomorrow then.
Goodbye, sir.
Okay, goodbye.
A BMW, huh?
What a treasure.
Dad.
I am in Aerospace City now,
in the newly built staff dorm.
It's a double room,
but Mr. Qin specially approved it for me alone.
Starting today,
I will live a life of muddling along.
Dad,
don't worry.
Take good care of yourself then.
I will talk to your mom.
Reporting to you, sir.
Newcomer Wu Wei reporting for duty.
Wu Wei?
You?
Why are you here?
What are you doing in my dorm?
You are staying here?
You...
Hello, Mr. Qin?
It's me.
Didn't we agree on a single dorm?
Why is there an extra person in my room?
What person?
There's an extra person living in my room.
It's a singles dorm.
He's also single.
You two share it.
The kind of single room you mentioned does exist,
but it's usually reserved for working couples,
and the environment isn't as good as here.
Wait until one opens up.
I'll take you to see it.
Just bear with it for now.
I can't bear it for another second.
Mr. Qin.
You promised me.
Please help me solve this quickly.
If you have a problem, say it to my face.
Why tattle behind my back?
I'm tattling to your face.
That was Aunt Chen on the day of the robotics competition, right?
She hasn't changed a bit.
Does she still
control you like when you were a kid?
None of your business.
Look at you.
You stole the championship,
and I didn't say anything.
We haven't seen each other for so many years.
Let's catch up.
It's better not to see each other.
Remember,
counting the rocket competition,
you owe me two.
Nobody owes you anything.
Take your stuff and leave.
What if I don't?
If you have a problem, move out.
Make some room for me.
As if anyone wants to live with you.
If anyone's moving, it's you.
Don't you understand first come, first served?
Whoever complains more moves out.
Aerospace City is all about ability.
Ability?
Do you have any?
Let's compete.
Are you an elementary schooler?
Then bring on a college-level one.
Come on, let me show you.
Fibonacci sequence.
Even elementary schoolers know it.
So what?
Based on the first set of solutions I gave,
find the second set.
Calculate it.
I'm timing you.
If you don't even understand the question,
don't talk about ability.
Who claimed
to be a Math Olympiad top student since childhood?
Me?
Apparently not.
Wait.
This question of yours has absolutely no mathematical correlation.
Stop bluffing.
Is it possible
that it's a geometric correlation?
Zero circles.
One, two, three.
Three circles.
Two, three, four.
Four circles.
One circle. One circle.
A kindergarten entrance exam question.
Understood? Applause.
Not convinced?
Give me one if you're not.
A leopard cannot change its spots.
One monkey riding on a tree, one monkey on the ground.
How many monkeys are there in total?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
No problem,
sorry about that.
Sorry.
Three-second rule. It's still good to eat.
I'm sorry.
Still good, no worries.
Ying.
I heard
you were specially recruited by Mr. Qin.
Nice to meet you.
You are indeed different.
Nice jacket and shoes.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm Cai Bo'ao.
You can call me Caibao.
Hello.
This is Qu Ruonan.
A top student from the University of Technology.
We attended an interview together before.
Qu Ruonan, nice to meet you.
Are you okay just now?
I'm fine, perfectly fine.
Let's go.
Registration is about to start.
Hurry up.
I also love chocolate.
Morning, Mr. Zhao.
I'm here to report.
You're here.
By the way, Wu Wei,
do you play chess?
No.
Get to work.
Mr. Zhao,
what should I do today?
What should I be busy with?
That pile of trash on the desk,
throw it away for me first.
That pile of paper?
Yes, that pile of paper.
Pick them out.
I told you to throw it away and you just did it?
You didn't even check if there's
any important data in this pile of trash.
Our archives are full of classified information.
What if there is
important data in this pile of trash?
Have you read the work manual?
Have you memorized the confidentiality rules?
Did you hear me? I'm asking you.
Mr. Zhao, it's my first day of work today.
So?
Is the first day of work an excuse?
Is it?
When was the work manual given to you?
Yesterday.
What did you do?
Mr. Zhao, I will definitely read it carefully.
If you have any requirements in the future,
you can tell me directly first.
Are you still unconvinced, kid?
Do you think I'm setting you up?
Yes.
I just want to test you.
If you really have confidence, would you be exposed?
Wu Wei.
The rules in Space City are rules.
This must be carved into your bones.
I shouldn't need to remind you again.
If you leak secrets, you will be caught.
If caught, you will be strictly punished.
Understood, Mr. Zhao.
Did you bring your work manual?
Yes,
in my bag.
Today, your job
is to carefully read the work manual.
After you finish reading,
help me move some things.
I hope you can understand.
This uniform represents honor,
responsibility,
expectation,
and duty.
The weight of this uniform
is far beyond what you can imagine right now.
From the moment you put on this uniform,
your destiny
is closely connected with every satellite.
Watching over them will be your lifelong mission.
This way.
All the work in our center
revolves around this big screen.
And is carried out here.
The upcoming Dragon Boat mission,
Ark return mission, Wentian mission,
and Haoyue mission.
All the work will be completed here.
Joint tests and rehearsals
will also be displayed on this big screen.
Our job
is to ensure that this aerospace nerve center
can operate accurately and methodically.
In recent years, our country's space missions
have been highly intensive.
The commands behind all missions
are issued from here.
The flight control work we are responsible for
is equivalent to the brain and heart of the entire mission.
Related emergency tasks
will also have their final decisions made here.
Including the control work for satellites,
which will also be completed here.
From today on,
you must quickly familiarize yourselves with this place.
Understand?
Excuse me,
sorry to interrupt everyone.
Everyone.
Mr. Qin.
This is our Flight Control Center's
Chief Qin Bojun.
Chief Qin.
I am the one who should bow.
Welcome, new generation of dream chasers.
This is our Flight Control Center,
where our dreams begin.
There are no
magnificent scenes of earth-shaking
and blazing flames
when every satellite is launched.
But in the future,
right here,
you will send little stars into the sky
and guard return capsules
as they safely return to Earth.
My requirement for you
from the first day you enter this hall,
is to
endure loneliness
and stand isolation.
You must learn
to work silently
in mountains of data.
A person's name will eventually disappear,
but his exploration of the boundless universe
will leave a mark,
turning into a set of data
and a radio wave in the vast universe.
Some countries look down on us in words,
but technologically,
they try every way to blockade us.
So as space professionals,
our mission
is to prove to the whole world
that not only can we complete the manned spaceflight project,
we will also become the first country in the world
to land on the far side of the moon.
And you will not only witness all this,
but also participate in it,
following every step
China's aerospace takes.
From a blank sheet of paper
to a sky full of stars,
it's the silent dedication of generations of space professionals.
They have spent their entire lives
making those Chinese stars
the brightest ones in the night sky.
The journey to space is long and the galaxy is vast.
Even in the farthest deep space,
we will leave our footprints.
I believe that
deep in the unknown universe,
there must be answers and truths
that humanity wants to know.
This is a journey
destined to have no end in sight,
but it is also the most romantic voyage.
Exploring space
has always been humanity's most beautiful dream.
And everyone sitting here
is a dream chaser.
China Aerospace.
Are you jealous?
Just rush right in,
find Mr. Qin and tell him
to give you another chance.
That's not appropriate, is it?
You know it's not appropriate too.
I'm sorry, Mr. Zhao.
Hurry up and leave.
The newcomers are here.
Newcomers are here.
Hello.
Hello, sir.
No need to be so polite.
I'm Hou Xingyu.
Just call me Hou from now on.
Let me introduce you.
Li Qitan,
call him Li.
He's an expert in remote sensing satellites.
This is Li Yanyan, Yan.
She is an expert in communication technology.
You should learn more from her in the future.
First of all, welcome to the flight control family.
Hou, you're being too modest.
Let me tell you,
Hou is very capable
when it comes to orbit control plans.
Most importantly, he's a very nice guy.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask him anytime.
Thank you all.
Oh, right.
This is You Xiu,
a very excellent man,
and also your senior.
Hello everyone.
You can call me You from now on.
You.
Senior You,
what part of the work are you responsible for?
He hit the nail on the head.
Although bragging isn't good,
I am actually
responsible for everything in flight control.
You can think of it like the libero
in basketball...
no, in volleyball.
Well...
Only an excellent man like me
can do this.
You know?
Got it.
Looking energetic.
Work hard from now on.
Wait.
We
prepared a welcome gift for everyone.
Some snacks and milk tea.
Just divide them among yourselves later.
Thank you all.
I actually also prepared
a little gift for everyone.
Quite thoughtful.
Yan.
Jia.
A small token of my appreciation.
Li.
Hou.
Okay.
Isn't this inappropriate?
Thanks.
How about this?
For future work,
Qu, you follow Li Qitan.
Communicate more about professional experience.
Cai Bo'ao, you follow Yanyan.
Ying Ziqi, you follow me.
You'll get familiar with the work gradually.
Right.
Our flight control center has a probation period.
To become regular employees,
your scores must meet the standard.
You can also consider it
as our center's KPI.
So you should feel some pressure now.
Pressure
creates motivation.
Where is my newbie?
I'm telling you,
you guys are really lucky.
Longzhou 1's
first rendezvous and docking
will take place tomorrow.
The superiors have approved
you three
to observe on site.
Watch carefully then.
Our aerospace
is marching towards the space station era.
Catching the first launch right after joining.
Cherish the opportunity.
Mr. Qin, have some milk tea.
No milk.
It upsets my stomach.
Jiajia will tell you the specific time.
Back to work.
Mr. Qin.
I've compiled last week's aerospace chronicle
and sent it to your email.
Take care.
Nan.
Did you see that?
I saw it.
Seamlessly opening the door
and taking credit for someone else's favor.
What a master.
No matter how much of a master he is,
he is no match for you,
the guy who gave out keychains.
I call this,
you can never have too many skills.
Learning the bad instead of the good.
These seniors are really amazing.
Why do I feel like
it's so hard to turn from an intern to a regular employee?
It's fine.
We have an expert.
Expert Ying is here.
Sister Nan.
Let's eat first.
Index Brother.
Excuse me, excuse me.
I knew it was you when I saw your hair.
How are you? How have you been?
Wu Wei.
Aren't you
Look at this,
an aerospace worker
working in the archives.
Are they making you do chores at the archives?
What are you talking about?
Nice to meet you. Wu Wei.
Qu Ruonan. Nice to meet you.
Tell us, tell us.
How have you been recently?
We're just paying our respects.
But we are going to the hall tomorrow
to participate in the launch.
Really?
They assigned you a task right after you came?
It's not exactly participating in a task.
It's the rendezvous and docking
of Dragon Boat-1 and Dragon Palace-2.
We're just observing.
Really?
Of course.
But to be honest,
if you were participating in a launch at the control center in the past,
it would take at least two or three years.
For us new people to
encounter a task right away,
this luck is
enough to win the lottery.
Index Brother,
aren't you going to take me to see it?
It's not convenient. Really not.
I don't think people from the archives can go.
Only people from the flight control can go.
And it needs the approval
of the supervisor.
Supervisor.
Please throw this away for me. Thank you.
Mr. Zhao.
I'm here.
You're out of breath.
The workload here
isn't that heavy.
After eating,
just stroll back.
If people see you like this,
they'll think this is a sweatshop.
Mr. Zhao,
I just ran into people from flight control.
They said the first rendezvous and docking
of Dragon Boat-1 is tomorrow.
So,
I want to go see it.
But they said
it needs the supervisor's approval.
Can you...
You want to go?
Yes, I do.
I've been very interested in aerospace since I was a child.
But I've only seen it on TV and the internet,
never with my own eyes.
Then go.
You know
where the flight control hall is.
Why don't you just go straight in?
But they said
it needs approval from the supervisor.
Right.
It does need the supervisor's approval.
Therefore, I don't approve it.
Wu Wei.
Do you think there's a place for you
in the flight control hall?
Should I get you a standing ticket,
or a folding stool?
Mr. Zhao, it's a misunderstanding.
I just thought
since there's a mission right after I came,
I could go and learn.
Don't call me that.
I haven't accepted you as my apprentice yet.
Learn?
What are you going to learn?
Wu Wei,
do you think
watching one mission
makes you an aerospace worker?
Do you think sitting in the flight control hall
makes you the chief dispatcher?
I asked you back then.
I asked if you were willing
to work in the archives.
You said you were.
As long as you could work here,
you were willing to do anything.
Good grief, it's only been a few days.
You haven't done anything yet,
and you're already scheming.
You're using this place as a stepping stone.
You're guarding such a huge archive
with so much data,
and you still think this place is too small for you?
Mr. Zhao.
That's not what I meant.
I don't care what you meant.
If this is your attitude,
you'd better leave as soon as possible.
I won't keep you here.
Mr. Zhao,
please assign the work for this afternoon.
Follow me.